Guide to the K. Ross Toole Archives Audio Recordings Collection 1962-2000
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
K. Ross Toole Archives Audio Recordings Collection
1962-2000
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana—Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 906
1.5 linear feet
This is an artificial collection of audio recordings held by the K. Ross Toole Archives. The recordings document activities at the University of Montana in Missoula including lectures, symposiums, speeches, and musical events.
This is a collection of audio recordings accumulated by the University of Montana's K. Ross Toole Archives from a variety of different sources. Recording formats include phonograph, cassette tape, and reel-to-reel tape. All of the audio in this collection pertains to various events and activities either hosted or participated in by the University of Montana (UM) including lectures, building dedications, event speeches, and convocations. Most of the recordings were produced by UM entities. Tape counter indexes and transcripts that were produced by the Archives exist for a few of the audio recordings in this collection.
These materials were organized numerically by item or folder number.
Most of the audio in this collection has been digitized by the Archives.
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana-Missoula.
Information about the original custodial history for most materials in this collection is unavailable. The majority of these materials were originally placed into the Archives' oral history collection. In 2017 they were removed, arranged and described as this artificial collection.
Acquisition information is available for some items in this collection.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
University of Montana--Missoula--Archives; University of Montana (Missoula, Mont.: 1965-1994); Montana State University (Missoula, Mont.); University of Montana--Missoula
Colleges and Universities
Sound recordings; Lectures
- Welcoming ceremony for President Richard C. Bowers and Mrs. Bowers, June 1974; audio format: Reel-to-reel (Box-item 1/001)
- Walley McRae lecture for the In Depth program hosted by the Center for Continuing Education and Summer Programs, January 1977; audio format: Reel-to-reel (Box-item 1/002)
- David Alt geology lecture for the Mortarboard Final Lecture series, January 27, 1977; audio format: Reel-to-reel (Box-item 1/003)
- Madeline DeFrees poetry lecture for the Mortarboard Final Lecture series, February 10, 1977; audio format: Reel-to-reel; This is only a partial audio recording. Tape cuts out in the middle of DeFrees' lecture. (Box-item 1/004)
- Richard Hugo poetry lecture for the "Off-Campus" series produced by the Center for Continuing Education and Summer Programs, March 3, 1977; audio format: Reel-to-reel (Box-item 1/005)
- Leslie Fiedler lecture for the Edmund and Mary Freeman Memorial Lecture series "Violence and Anti-Violence in Literature and Popular Arts", October 30, 1980; audio format: Reel-to-reel (Box-item 1/006)
- K. Ross Toole's remarks at Clancy Gordon's memorial service, July 17, 1981; audio format: Reel-to-reel (Box-item 1/007)
- Henrietta Whiteman lecture "Native American Perspectives and Competencies", July 24, 1974; audio format: 60-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/008)
- President Richard C. Bowers State of the University Address, January 21, 1975; audio format: 60-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/009)
- Gary Kimball lecture on Native American history in Montana, Part 1, June 13, 1978; audio format: 120-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/010)
- Gary Kimball lecture on Native American history in Montana, Part 2, June 13, 1978; audio format: 120-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/011)
- Mansfield Library Dedication, October 12, 1979; audio format: 90-min cassette tape; Speakers include K. Ross Toole and UM President Richard C. Bowers (Box-item 2/012)
- Lester Thurow lecture for the Edmund and Mary Freeman Memorial Lecture series "The Death of American Productivity", 1982; audio format: 60-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/013)
- Authors Richard Hugo and James Welch reading their work, Part 1, circa 1970s; audio format: 60-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/014)
- Authors Richard Hugo and James Welch reading their work, Part 2, circa 1970s; audio format: 60-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/015)
- K. Ross Toole memorial service, 1981; audio format: 60-min cassette tape; Speakers include Harry Fritz and Daniel Kemmis (Box-item 2/016)
- University of Montana convocation welcoming incoming President Neil Bucklew, 1981; audio format: 60-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/017)
- Ben Stout dedication speech for the University Forest and Conservation Experiment Station's Lubrecht Experimental Forest, October 7, 1983; audio format: 90-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/018)
- K. Ross Toole Archives and Special Collections dedication ceremony, November 4, 1983; audio format: 60-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/019)
- Frank B. Linderman collection opening in the Mansfield Library's Archives and Special Collections, October 26, 1984; audio format: 90-min cassette tape; Speakers include President Neil Bucklew, William Bevis, Dean R. Patrick, and Sarah Hatfield (Box-item 2/020)
- Dorothy Johnson collection opening in the Mansfield Library's Archives and Special Collections, October 11, 1985; audio format: 60-min cassette tape; Speakers include President Neil Bucklew and Dr. Warren J. Brier (Box-item 2/021)
- Lucile Speer memorial service, January 30, 1988; audio format: 90-min cassette tape; Speakers include Tom MacElwain, Johanna Hays, Theresa Lucile MacElwain, Judge Gordon Bennett and Marge Brown (Box-item 2/022)
- Joe Dixon Papers collection opening in the Mansfield Library's Archives and Special Collections, October 1988; audio format: 60-min cassette tape; Speakers include Lynn Schwanke, Ruth Patrick, President James Koch, and Dale Johnson (Box-item 2/023)
- Mike Hardy lecture "1988 and Earlier: Forest Fires", October 28, 1988; audio format: 60-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/024)
- President James Koch speech to UM faculty about plans for campus buildings and programs, April 21, 1989; audio format: 90-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/025)
- Robert Pantzer lecture for the UM Centennial class taught by Dale Johnson, February 3, 1993; audio format: 60-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/026)
- Robert Pantzer lecture for the UM Centennial class taught by Dale Johnson, February 10, 1993; audio format: 60-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/027)
- Don Habbe lecture for the UM Centennial class taught by Dale Johnson, February 12, 1993; audio format: 60-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/028)
- Mary Ann Campbell lecture for the UM Centennial class taught by Dale Johnson, February 24, 1993; audio format: 60-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/029)
- Maxine Van de Wetering lecture "20 Years of Women's Studies Programs", March 9, 1994; audio format: 120-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/030)
- Groundbreaking of the Gallagher Business Building, April 28, 1994; audio format: 90-min cassette tape; Speakers include Larry Gianchetta and George Dennison (Box-item 2/031)
- Don Oberdorfer lecture "Reflecting on the Life of Mike Mansfield", June 2000; audio format: 120-min cassette tape (Box-item 2/032)
- Kyi-Yo Pow-wow live recording of drumming at event, 1973; audio format: 12-inch phonograph record (Box-item OS 4/033)
- The Columbians at Montana State University Jazz Festival, 1962; audio format: 7-inch phonograph record (Box-item 3/034)
- Tape counter index for audio 003, 1 (Box-folder 3/1)
- Tape counter index for audio 009, 1975 (Box-folder 3/2)
- Tape counter index for audio 012, 1979 (Box-folder 3/3)
- Tape counter index for audio 006, 1980 (Box-folder 3/4)
- Tape counter index for audio 013, 1982 (Box-folder 3/5)
- Tape counter index for audio 016, 1981 (Box-folder 3/6)
- Tape counter index for audio 017, 1981 (Box-folder 3/7)
- Tape counter index for audio 018, 1983 (Box-folder 3/8)
- Tape counter index for audio 020, 1984 (Box-folder 3/9)
- Tape counter index for audio 021, 1985 (Box-folder 3/10)
- Tape counter index for audio 022, 1988 (Box-folder 3/11)
- Tape counter index for audio 023, 1988 (Box-folder 3/12)
- Tape counter index for audio 024, 1988 (Box-folder 3/13)
- Tape counter index for audio 028, 1993 (Box-folder 3/14)